Hello and welcome back to another
episode with ItsDrDan and today
we're going to be looking at the
formation of triacylglycerides.
So with these particular compounds this
is a part of our lipid series where
we're going to be looking at different
introductory biochemistry reactions.
So with this one in particular is
how do I form a triacylglyceride?
Well it's pretty straight
forward how to do it.
So if I have a glycerol, which is a three
member alcohol, so we see three alcohols.
on this structure and it's
attached to three carbons.
I always recommend drawing it this
way and what this is going to connect
to is to three separate fatty acids.
So whenever we have a fatty acid
chain I replace the R group, uh, the
long carbon chain with an R group.
Usually what these look like
is these giant long chains
just like the one up here.
So we have the glycerol right here on the
far left and we can see like little tiny
polar region of the fat or the oil here.
And then that's going to be connected
to this very, very long fatty acid.
So when the way this reaction works
is pretty easy what we're going
to be doing is removing water to
connect the two fragments So what
I always do is I line up the h2os.
So if you see here we got h2o H2o
with my little androids h2o and what
we're gonna be doing is removing that
water piece Okay, so if I copy and
paste this down right here and I move
it down below We are just going to
be copying and pasting that piece.
So we're getting rid of the
water part, just like so, boop
boop, and deleting all those.
And now what we're going to do is
merge these two parts together.
So when that happens, we now have our
fatty acids that are now connecting.
To our, our structure, and
this is what we call a glycerol
carboxylate, or our triacylglyceride.
Now keep in mind here, the ending,
right, so before if we had a fatty
acid, it would be that carboxylic acid.
But being that this is referring to
that it's, it's the salt form that
this turns into before it bonds.
It's going to have that 8
ending when we name these, okay?
So it's glycerol, and it's
going to be a carboxylate.
So when you see a name, you're
looking for the 8 ending when it's
referring to the large structure.
You want to draw the condensed
structural formula for glycerol.
Tripalumetoliate.
Now, how would you do that?
Well, generally, you have
a reference sheet available
to you with a lot of these.
You can, you have to look up
what the components are for it.
Maybe in your class you have to memorize
the different lipids, but hopefully not.
What you're gonna be doing is
there's two components, right?
So the first one is glycerol.
What I would recommend doing is if you are
taking a biochemistry course is memorize
what the structure of glycerol looks like.
Remember, there's going to be three
carbons connected to each other, and each
one of them is going to have an OH group.
Now, I already provided poly,
polymetholeic acid, which is the fatty
acid that's going to be used here.
So what we're going to do is
we're going to put these and
line them up next to each other.
Now, notice with this structure,
we don't have enough acids.
So it's going to take three of
them for this to happen, right?
So all this is going to be occurring
under, um, just under, usually under
acidic conditions or usually or maybe
it's being heated when this is happening.
So we will have our three
different components.
So we're going to have three
of them lined up just like so.
And what are we going to be removing?
is we're going to be removing
water as a result, right.
So just like how we did before,
we're going to copy and paste
those guys so that we can show
the full complete reaction, right.
So when that happens, and being
these are such big molecules,
usually you have to use multiple
lines of a notebook to do that.
So we're going to erase all of the OH
or water components with the structure.
That is going to be our product, right?
So we're making three waters, uh,
part of, as part of our reaction.
This is going to combine it together
to make our, our, uh, final product
here, which was the glycerol tri, uh,
palomeoliate is what our final product is.
Now, so just as a reminder,
what type of reaction is this?
Well, this is a form of a
condensation reaction, right?
So you're removing water to make
this very, very large compound.
And that's the complete
reaction of how to do this.
I hope that this video helped
and please hit that like and
subscribe button if it did.
And please look at my other lipid
videos so you can learn more
about these different reactions.
All right, I'll see y'all later now.
Bye now.